ALTON OBINNA OKWUONU

PLOT 9, SFAX STREET, WUSE ZONE 4, ABUJA, NIGERIA.

Portfolio Website: https://alton-portfolio.vercel.app

+2348128169641 altonobinna@yahoo.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A full stack software developer and ICT specialist creating top-notch web and mobile applications through full-code and low-code tools. My expertise in the field of ICT and software development enables me to oversee the ICT operations of my organization whilst developing software (internal/external) required to optimize operations of my organization whenever the need arises.

PERSONAL DETAILS

SEX: Male

DATE OF BIRTH: 25th April 1991

MARITAL STATUS: Single

NATIONALITY: Nigeria

LANGUAGES SPOKEN: English (Fluent)

<u>6 MONTH ONLINE DIPLOMA SPECIALIZATION CERTIFICATIONS</u>

- Meta Front-End Developer Professional Specialization. META Organization, USA.
- Web Development and Coding Diploma Specialization. University of Michigan, USA.
- Fintech: Foundations and Applications of Financial Technology. University of Pennsylvania, USA.
- Financial Technology Innovation Diploma Specialization. University of Michigan, USA.
- Data Analysis and Presentation Diploma Specialization. PricewaterhouseCoopers, USA.
- Advanced Business Analytic Diploma Specialization. University of Colorado, Boulder, USA.
- Digital Marketing Strategy Diploma Specialization. Interactive Advertising Bureau, Europe and Google, USA.
- Post Graduate Diploma in Information Technology. HIIT Training Institute, NIGERIA.
- Market Research Diploma Specialization. University of California, Davis, USA.

EDUCATION

- Master of Social Science in International Business Economics (Full Time). January 2013 July 2014. Anglia Ruskin University, Cambridge, United Kingdom.
- Bachelor of Social Science in Economics (Honors) October 2006- December 2010. University of Abuja, Nigeria.

WORK EXPERIENCE.

VALTON HOTELS LIMITED.

ICT MANAGER (JANUARY 2018 – DECEMBER 2022).

- Oversight on ICT installation, configuration, optimization and troubleshooting.
- Principal ICT officer for general computer support, software installations, license management, networks, printers, audio/video conferencing and mobile phone support, deployment of equipment and management of ICT inventories.
- Development of software required to synchronize and boost internal/external operations of organization's activities.
- Set up of equipment such as laptops, data projectors, interactive whiteboards, sound systems and other specialist ICT equipment, ensuring that systems are ready for use and operating correctly.
- Proactive monitoring and maintenance of telecommunications equipment to avoid interruption of services.
- Consistent and timely troubleshooting support provided to all ICT projects and organization's personnel.
- Proactive assessment of user needs in terms of ICT software and installation of the same on computers for all relevant users.
- Establishment of control systems to ensure that all information technology equipment is maintained regularly and in proper working condition.
- Ongoing proactive evaluation of system performance, identifying areas of inefficiencies and potential problems.
- Ensuring security of information technology operation at all times. Development of back-up programmes and ensuring strict implementation.
- Ensuring availability of strong, reliable and adequate internet connectivity within organization.
- Identification of new areas where computerization is advantageous and applicable. Recommendation of applicable software packages to use, understanding user/clients specification, needs and requirements to achieve client satisfaction.
- Technical support provided to the supply chain management department in defining specifications for ICT related equipment and services; and participation in procurement bid evaluations as a technical expert.
- Technical support provided to projects and personnel in designing ICT related systems and platforms for automation of processes.
- Create and amend necessary support documentation to ensure known errors and troubleshooting guidance is recorded, assisting colleagues in resolution of ICT issues and ensuring a foundation of appropriate technical knowledge is maintained.
- Implementation of corporate information technology policy changes applicable to the organization, if any, to be compatible and up to par with ICT plan.
- Maintenance of ICT inventories including Media Library, Software Assets, Hardware Assets, Communications Lines etc.
- Preparation of trainings and seminars required to optimize organization's staff usage of relevant ICT software.
- All warranty supporting documentation and materials are kept safe, secure and accessible during the validity period of each warranty.
- Creation and maintenance of effective database system with regards to ICT operations and activities of the organization.
- Provision of ICT reports, required for management information and as tool for decision-making.

NIGERIAN NATIONAL PETROLEUM CORPORATION, ABUJA NIGERIA.

AUDITOR (NYSC/PROJECT STAFF) JULY 2011- DECEMBER 2012.

- Audit of employee's wage and touring advance, third party contractor payment vouchers and corporate social donations.
- Preparation of efficient daily, weekly, monthly and annual financial data reports in regards to payment vouchers approved or queried.
- Audit of merchandise supplied to Corporation in order to ensure quality assurance.

SKILLS SUMMARY.

- Takes initiative.
- Top-notch software development expertise.
- Optimal ICT skillset.
- Good planning, time management, analytical, critical thinking, detail oriented, problem solving and organizational skills.
- Strong safety awareness.
- Exceptional verbal communication skills.
- Excellent interpersonal skills and ability to effectively communicate with a variety of interdisciplinary teams and non-technical users.
- Honest, trustworthy and a high work ethic.
- Outstanding diagnostic, problem-solving and analytical skills
- Multitasking skills and ability to meet deadlines.
- Ability to work independently as well as in a team.

EXTRA- CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES.

- · Working out and engaging in sporting activities inclusive of lawn and table tennis, squash, cycling.
- Having healthy conversations and debates.